(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 1000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
大空スバル 7周年LIVE ラブミ❣
[Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live: LOVE ME!]
7th Anniversary
COUNTDOWN
ラブミ❣
[Title: LOVE ME!]
しゅわー！
Shuwa!
ホロライブ2期生、
Hololive 2nd Gen,
大空スバルっす！
it's Oozora Subaru!
今日はみんな
Everyone,
楽しんでってねー！
please enjoy yourselves today!
ちょこっとヤンチャで
A little bit mischievous,
ニコっと元気な
grinning and full of energy...
元気なキラッとスマイル　アイドル
A cheerful, sparkling smile, an idol
毎日もっと楽しくしたい
I want to make every day more fun
Do you know? With adventure!
ひらひらスカートも
Even a fluttering skirt
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear it properly
だからもっともっと好きになってもいいよ
So it's okay to like me more and more
一緒に
Together
大空に飛び立とう
Let's fly away into the big sky
Hikare Sunrise どんな輝きの中でも
Shine Sunrise, even in any kind of brilliance
強い煌めき
A strong sparkle
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if only a millimeter gets across, that's fine
Oh Charge! Challenge! 全力アクセル
Oh Charge! Challenge! Full throttle
頑張る君へ
To you, who's working hard
1番乗りのスマイルを送る
I'll send you the very first smile
Subaru Channel!
Everyday 悩んでみんなで
Every day, worrying together with everyone
憂鬱な気持ちにズバッと駆けつけ
Rushing in to deal with those gloomy feelings
お助けしちゃうヒロイン
A heroine who'll come to the rescue
弱いハートじゃいられないから
Because I can't stay with a weak heart
強気で行きましょう
Let's go with confidence!
ハラハラ水際で
On the edge, nervously
ドキドキのときめきタイム
A heart-pounding, thrilling time
いつでもおいでよ 1年中パラダイス
Come anytime, it's paradise all year round
ドカンと
With a bang
曇り空吹き飛ばそう
Let's blow away the cloudy skies
Agare Sunrise どんな暗闇の中でも
Rise Sunrise, even in any kind of darkness
眩しく照らす
Shining brightly
君に見つけてもらえた
You found me
それだけでも運命なんだ
That alone is destiny
もっとずっと道は続いてく
The road continues much further
夢に向かって
Towards our dreams
一緒に来てくれるかな
Will you come with me?
その手取って走れ
Take that hand and run
連れて行くよ みんなで
I'll take you there, all together
輝く 恥ずかしいけれど
Shining, though it's embarrassing
伝えたい想い
The feelings I want to convey
今なら言える
Now, I can say it
君のエールが力になるよ
Your cheers give me strength
いつも元気を分けてくれて
Always sharing your energy with me
頑張っていけるんだ
I can keep working hard
笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
I can spend my days laughing, truly
ありがとうの気持ちを
These feelings of gratitude
歌え Sunrise どんな輝きの中でも
Sing it, Sunrise, even in any kind of brilliance
強い煌めき
A strong sparkle
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if only a millimeter gets across, that's fine
もっとずっと道は続いてく
The road continues much further
夢に向かって
Towards our dreams
一緒に来てくれるかな
Will you come with me?
その手取って走れ
Take that hand and run
連れて行くよ みんなで
I'll take you there, all together
君とかける Subaru
Running with you, Subaru
大空スバル 7周年ライブ！
Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live!
始まる、始まるー！！
It's starting, it's starting!!
いつも迷惑ばっかりかけるけど
I always cause trouble for you
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
I always end up making you worry
それでも隣にいてくれる
But even so, you stay beside me
君の側に　ずっと
By your side, forever
曖昧な言葉じゃ
With vague words
真面目な君には伝わらない
I know they don't reach you, who are so serious
頑丈なそのハートを
Your heart is built very tough
覗いてみたい
I want to peek into it
溶かしてみたい
I want to melt it
そんな時　こんな魔法はどうかな
How about this kind of magic for those moments?
（何が出るかな？）（やっちゃえ）
(What will come out? Go ahead!)
セーノ　Try Try Try
Ready, Try Try Try
あやふやだって　（いいの　いいの）
Even if it's unclear (It's okay, it's okay)
Which one to pick? Watch me do magic
あらら　想像以上の展開
Wow, an outcome beyond imagination
もう止められないのよ　ごめんなさい
I can't stop anymore, I'm sorry
溢れる思い出から回り
Overflowing memories, spinning around
...けどほら
...but look
こんなDay by dayがいい
This kind of Day by day is good
あの日から Falling in love with you
Since that day, Falling in love with you
変わらないから ずっと Only you
Because it doesn't change, always Only you
だからほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, it's no time to be idle
掴めハッピーエンディング
Grasp the happy ending
いつまでも隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to be laughing by your side forever
いつも仲間はずれで 独りぼっちの毎日
Always an outcast, lonely every day
そんな私の前に 現れた君は
You who appeared before such a me
同じ淋しさを 抱えている
Are carrying the same loneliness
とても とても 優しい人
A very, very kind person
今も心配事は多いけど
There are still many worries now, but...
もう私も君も 一人じゃない
Already, neither I nor you are alone
騒がしくて愛おしい この日々が
These noisy and lovely days
ずっと 続きますように
May they continue forever
3 2 1
飛ばせ Happy なイメージ
Fly, a happy image
とびきりの Fancy なマジック
The best fancy magic
また君に くどくど言われそうだけど
I might be nagged by you again, but...
そんな Day by day がいい
That kind of Day by day is good
あの日から Falling in love with you
Since that day, Falling in love with you
気付いて欲しいの Loving you
I want you to notice, Loving you
だからほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, it's no time to be idle
次はどんなプランニング
What's the next planning?
そしてまた今日もハプニング 明日はどんな
And again today there's a happening, what about tomorrow...
おかしなことが起こるかな
...strange thing will happen?
ずっと 隣で見ててね
Watch me by my side forever
Happy image
Fancy magic
ハイタッチ☆メモリー (LIVE High-Touch Summer ver.)
[Title: High-Touch☆Memory (LIVE High-Touch Summer ver.)]
いっせーので 君とだけ！
One, two, only with you!
もう少し眠りたいけど
I want to sleep a little more, but...
もったいないよ 今日は Sunday
It's a waste, today is Sunday
楽しいこと やりたいこと Wake up! 始めようよ
Fun things, things I want to do. Wake up! Let's start
めくりめく季節 君と 次のステージへ
Changing seasons with you, to the next stage
声を合わせ 扉開けて 駆け出せ迷わずに
Join our voices, open the door, run out without hesitating
転んでも かっこわるくてもイイじゃない
Even if I fall, even if it's not cool, it's fine
Stand up! イメージ もっと 重ねて行くその先で
Stand up! Layer more images, and beyond that...
いっせーので 君とだけ！
One, two, only with you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて 奏でるメロディーを
High-five, clap hands, the melody we play...
合図に走り出せ Go! 君とならこわくない
Start running at the signal, Go! With you I'm not afraid
ハイタッチ 手と手叩いて 重ねるそのメモリーは
High-five, clap hand to hand, those memories we stack...
明日へのエネルギー Yeah! さあ行こうよもっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow. Yeah! Let's go further ahead
君となら Happy Lucky Life! (ハピラキラ)
With you, Happy Lucky Life!
あの日見た夢の続き 追いつくその日まで
Until the day I catch up to the continuation of the dream I saw that day
涙なんて振り切るくらい もっとスピードアップ
Speed up more, enough to shake off the tears
どんな未来になっても 後悔しないよ
No matter what future it becomes, I won't regret it
自分自身 選んだ道 踏み出せ迷わずに
The path I chose myself, step out without hesitating
落ち込んで 進めなくなった時は
When you are down and can't move forward,
Wake up! 思い返す 夢見た頃の記憶を
Wake up! Look back on the memories of the time you dreamed
手と手で 奏でる 叶える 煌めく 夢を 君とだけ！
Hand in hand, play, fulfill, sparkling dream, only with you!
ハイタッチ その度に 繋がっていく心
High-five, every time, our hearts connect
一人じゃないことを そう 気付かせてくれたよね
I realized I'm not alone, didn't I?
ハイタッチ 手と手叩いて 奏でるそのメロディーが
High-five, clap hand to hand, the melody you play...
世界に届くまで Yeah! この夢は続いてく
...until it reaches the world. Yeah! This dream continues
君となら Happy Lucky Live! (ハピラキラ)
With you, Happy Lucky Live!
くじいて歩けない日は おんぶしてあげる君を
On days when I'm discouraged and can't walk, I'll carry you on my back
ほら見てそっちの方が 強く地面 踏み込める
Look, this way I can step on the ground more strongly
めくりめくる日々を
In the revolving days,
たどり夢見たステージへ
follow them to the stage we dreamed of
届くその日を見つめて 起こそう君とだけ！
watch the day it reaches, let's cause it with just you!
いっせーので 君とだけ！
One, two! With just you!
手と手を鳴らす度
Every time we clap hands
小さなビッグバン
A small big bang
無限のそのチカラを
Receive the power of the infinite
受けて進め！
and move forward!
ハイタッチ
High-touch
手たたいて
Clap hands
奏でるメロディーを
The melody we play
合図に走り出せ Go！
Use it as a signal and run out, go!
君とならこわくない
I'm not afraid if I'm with you
ハイタッチ
High-touch
手と手叩いて
Clap hands and hands
重ねるそのメモリーは
The memory we stack is
明日へのエネルギー Yeah！
energy for tomorrow, yeah!
さあ行こうよもっと先へ
Let's go, even further ahead
君となら Happy Lucky Life！
With you, happy lucky life!
というわけで皆さん、おはスバ〜！
So then everyone, Oha-Suba~!
大空スバル 7周年記念ライブ「ラブミ！」にお越しくださり
Thank you for coming to Oozora Subaru's
ありがとうございます！
7th Anniversary Live "LOVE ME!"
いえーい！
Yay!
始まります！このライブ、大空スバル、よろしくお願いします！
It's starting! I'm Oozora Subaru, please take care of me!
ということで、ついにラブミが始まる始まる〜！
And so, finally "LOVE ME" is starting, starting~!
今日の配信のハッシュタグは右上のこちらになりますので
Today's stream hashtag is this one in the top right,
ぜひよろしくお願いします！
so please use it!
いっぱい「#大空スバル7周年LIVE」をつけてたくさん呟いてください！
Please tweet a lot with the hashtag #OozoraSubaru7thAnniversaryLIVE!
スバルもチェックしたいと思います！
Subaru will also be checking them!
そして皆さん、気づきましたか？
And everyone, did you notice?
なんと！今までも可愛かったんですけど...
What! I was already cute until now...
でも！より可愛くしていただきました！ニュー・スバルです！
But! They made me even cuter! This is New Subaru!
よろしくお願いします！
Please take care of me!
どうですか？可愛い？
How is it? Is it cute?
可愛い〜！
So cute~!
ぜひたくさんスクショ撮って、ツイート... ポストしてください！
Please take lots of screenshots and tweet... I mean post them!
通常のスバルも見たいので、ちょっと着替えてきていいですか？
I want to see the regular Subaru too, so can I go change for a bit?
着替えてきます！じゃあ行ってきます！
I'll go change! See you soon!
通常衣装のニュー・スバル！
New Subaru in regular outfit!
そしてなんと、帽子がない！ついに取れるようになった！
And what, no hat! I can finally take it off!
やったー！ついに取れるようになりました！
Yay! I can finally take it off!
どうですか？可愛いですか？
How is it? Is it cute?
とてもより可愛く作っていただきました。髪の毛もさらさら〜
They made me much cuter. My hair is so silky~
もう本当に、ありがとうございます！
Really, thank you so much!
そして可愛いといえば、なんと、こちらのステージ！
And speaking of cute, look at this stage!
スバルはゲームが好きなので、ピクセルっぽい感じで作っていただきました！
I love games, so they made it with this pixel-y feel!
いえーい！スバルドダックもいる！
Yay! Subaru-duck is here too!
そしてなんといっても、このピクセルスバ友！
And above all, these pixel Subatomo!
めっちゃ可愛いです。これが一番見せたかったと言っても過言ではない！
They're so cute. It's no exaggeration to say this is what I wanted to show you most!
こんな素敵なステージでさせていただきます。とっても幸... あ〜！
I'll be performing on this wonderful stage. I'm so happ... Ah~!
なんと！しれっと着替えてきました！こんにちは！
What! I changed back without you noticing! Hello!
やっぱね、アイドル衣装でやっていきたいと思いますので、
After all, I want to perform in my idol outfit,
ぜひアイドル衣装スバルもいっぱい撮ってポストしてください！
so please take lots of photos of idol outfit Subaru too and post them!
はい、ということでここまでは
Yes, and so, up until now,
「プリアデス」「ウォッチミー」「ハイタッチ☆メモリー」をお届けしました！
I've delivered "Pleiades", "Watch Me", and "High-Touch! Memory"!
全てスバルにとって思い出深い楽曲で...
They are all very memorable songs for Subaru...
特に「プリアデス」は、ニュー・スバルになったら一番に披露したかったんです。
Especially "Pleiades", I really wanted to perform it first as New Subaru.
夢が叶ってめっちゃ嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
My dream came true and I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
はい、ということでここからはなんと...
Yes, and so, from here on, what...
何が起こるかわからない！ゲストが出てくるかもしれないし、こないかもしれない！
You don't know what's going to happen! Guests might appear, or they might not!
何が起こるかわからないライブをお楽しみに！
Please look forward to this unpredictable live!
このあともどんどん盛り上がって楽しんでいくぞ！
Let's keep getting excited and having fun after this!
始まる、始まる〜！
It's starting, starting~!
私の全力受け止めて♡
Receive all of my power♡
めにしゅきラッシュっしゅ！
Menishuki Rashushu!
Accept my full power!
きゅんきゅん らたっちゅら めにめに
Kyunkyun ratacchura meni-meni
きゅんきゅん らたっちゅら しゅきしゅきしゅきしゅき
Kyunkyun ratacchura shuki-shuki-shuki-shuki
きゅんきゅん らたっちゅら めにめに Oh yeah
Kyunkyun ratacchura meni-meni Oh yeah
きゅんきゅんきゅんとくんとー？ 「てんきゅっきゅん」
Kyun-kyun-kyun tokun-to? "Tenkyu-kyun!"
例えばタイムループなんかしちゃったって
For example, even if I did a time loop,
運命で選んじゃうのはキミ (Yeah yeah yeah)
The one I'd choose by fate is you (Yeah yeah yeah)
だしっと一斉全体いや絶対！
Totally, no, absolutely!
シンデレラフィットなのは そうキミ (Oh oh oh)
The one who's a Cinderella fit is you (Oh oh oh)
わたしが何度も負けて落ち込んだって
Even if I lose many times and get depressed,
めげずに特訓付き合っちゃって
You don't give up and keep me company in training,
モチベ上げるだけぶち上げちゃって (ななな ななななな)
Raising my motivation, just cheering me up (Na-na-na...)
ステップアップめっちゃしちゃって 勝って一緒に喜びあって
Taking step-ups, winning and rejoicing together,
うぅー！感謝してもしきれないんじゃ～！
Ugh! I can't thank you enough!
カタチだけなんてナンセンス
It's nonsense to care only about form.
カタチないものがいいんです
I like things without form.
えーっとね それはなんと云いますか
Umm... how should I say that...
わっ 待って待って！ 今ここで伝えたいんです！
Ah, wait, wait! I want to convey it right here!
月並みだけど届けたい想い
It's a cliché, but I want to deliver my feelings.
「こんなに大きくなりました♡」
"I've grown so much"
だから ちょーmany-manyな約束どかっとリリース
So, a super many-many promise, delivered to you.
もりもりmany-many返すから！
I'll return it with many-many more!
いつだって しゅきしゅきしゅきしゅきスプリームなお願い聞いて！
Always, listen to my shuki-shuki Supreme request!
わたし会いたーい Day by day
I want to see you day by day.
ちょーmany-manyぎゅーぎゅぎゅっとエールをリリース
Super many-many gyu-gyu-gyutto cheer, delivered to you.
絶対ゼッタイ倍で返すから！
I'll return it, absolutely, absolutely double!
手渡しじゃ何年かかるかな
I wonder how many years it would take to hand it over.
ヘビーすぎじゃない！？ でもねいいんじゃない！？
Isn't it too heavy!? But isn't it okay??
Gimme!! いつも愛をアリ・ガ・トゥー
Gimme!! Always, love, th-a-n-k y-o-u!
甘いだけじゃダメだけどね
It can't just be sweet, but...
今日くらいは許してよ… hum
For today at least, please forgive me... hum.
大事な話だからもうちょ～～～～～っと
It's an important talk, so just a bit loooooonger.
ときめきだけで言えるかな
I wonder if I can say it with just excitement.
誠心誠意聴いてくれますか？
Will you listen with all your heart?
Ah～ (うぉー！)
Ah~ (Uwoah!)
だから ちょーmany-manyな約束どかっとリリース
So, a super many-many promise, delivered to you.
もりもりmany-many返すから！
I'll return it with many-many more!
いつだって しゅきしゅきしゅきしゅきスプリームなお願い聞いて！
Always, listen to my shuki-shuki Supreme request!
わたし会いたーい
I want to see you.
Day by day ちょーmany-manyぎゅーぎゅぎゅっとエールをリリース
Day by day, super many-many gyu-gyu-gyutto cheer, delivered to you.
絶対ゼッタイ倍で返すから！
I'll return it, absolutely, absolutely double!
手渡しじゃ何年かかっても
Even if it takes years to hand it over,
会いたいじゃない！ 届けたいじゃない！
I want to see you! I want to reach you!
Gimme!! いつも愛をアリ・ガ・トゥー
Gimme!! Always, love, th-a-n-k y-o-u!
もっみゅん♡
Momyun! ♡
きゅっきゅん らたっちゅら めにめに Oh yeah
Kyu-kyun ratacchura meni-meni Oh yeah
きゅんきゅんきゅんとくんとー？
Kyun-kyun-kyun tokun-to?
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅんきゅんきゅん！
Kyun-kyun-kyun-kyun-kyun-kyun!
ずーっとよろしくね！
Always be with me, okay!
ゆらゆらり はらはらり
いろとりどり みだれ咲き
Swaying gently, fluttering down,
In a riot of colors, blooming wildly.
花の街 思い出す
この空から
From this sky,
I remember the city of flowers.
[Title: 百花繚乱]
[Title: Hyakka Ryoran (Profusion of Flowers)]
ひょんな出来事から やってきたこの場所は
Through an unexpected turn of events, I arrived at this place,
遥か遠くにあった 煌びやかな舞台
A glittering stage that once seemed so far away.
ハッとするほど鮮やかな世界が あるんだと知った
I learned that a world so breathtakingly vivid truly exists,
あなたの無理難題に 答えていく どんな旅に
Responding to your impossible demands, on whatever journey it may be.
あっと言わせるような奇想天外な 答え合わせで
With an astonishing, out-of-the-box checking of answers,
辿り着いたその先に 新しい景色が待っているんだ
A new landscape is waiting at the end of the road we've reached.
摩訶不思議なミステリー 次から次に起こるたび
Every time a profound mystery occurs one after another,
巧妙なからくりも 暴いてみせましょう
I'll expose even the most ingenious mechanisms.
どんな難題でも 種や仕掛けはあるんだ
No matter how difficult the problem, there's always a trick or a gimmick.
副作用は気にしない 必ず闇導き出すから
I don't care about side effects; I'll definitely lead us out of the darkness.
あぁ この場所で触れた 人の悲しみや喜びがある
Ah, in this place, there are the sorrows and joys of the people I've touched.
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
Every single one of them makes my heart tremble.
はっとしちゃうほど鮮やかな世界が ここにあるんだ
A world so vivid it takes your breath away is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 答えていく毎日に
In these days of responding to your impossible demands,
あっと言わせるような奇想天外な 答え合わせで
With an astonishing, out-of-the-box checking of answers...
...辿り着いたその先に
...reached that destination,
新しい私が待っているんだ
a new version of me is waiting.
あの頃は 想像もしてない
Back then, I couldn't even imagine
未来が咲き始めてる
that the future would start to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
Maybe these days aren't so bad.
ゆらり ひらり
Swaying, fluttering,
離れては 寄り添って
drifting apart then drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ
Entrusting my body to the gentle breeze,
夕闇に舞う
I dance in the twilight.
KONNANじゃないっ!
[Title: Not Like This!]
アノユメも アコガレも
Those dreams, that admiration,
落書きのままボヤけて
blurring while still just graffiti,
消えろ寸前
on the verge of disappearing.
「コレガイイノ?」「コレデイイノ?」
"Is this okay?" "Is this really okay?"
ふてくされてる鏡に
To my sulking mirror,
何度も問いかけた
I questioned again and again.
泣きたい日も
Even on days I want to cry,
くじけそうな日も
even on days I feel like giving up,
乗り越えよう
let's overcome it.
希望を浴びなきゃ
Unless I bathe in hope,
夢というツボミは
the flower bud of my dream
開かないから
won't open.
Are you ready GO! 走り出そう!
Are you ready GO! Let's start running!
取り急ぎ さぁスタート!
In a hurry, start now!
うつむかない! ふりむかない!
Don't look down! Don't look back!
明日は絶対もっとShiny!
Tomorrow will definitely be even more Shiny!
ジブン次第! 掴め未来!
It's up to me! Seize the future!
今すぐスタートボタン
Let's press the start button
押してみよう
right now.
私は こんなんじゃないはず!
I am, this can't be all there is!
3, 2, 1, GO!
あきらめも 言い訳も
Bundle up the resignation and excuses
取りまとめリスタート!
and let's restart!
『たられば』に すがるには
Are you still too young
まだまだ若すぎじゃない?
to cling to "if onlys"?
七転び八起きでGO!
Fall seven times, rise eight, GO!
何度もリセットボタン
No matter how many times I press the reset button,
どんな夢も きっと
surely, any dream
困難じゃないはず
won't be difficult.
信じてみよう
Believe in it.
私は こんなんじゃないはず!
I am, this can't be all there is!
Are you ready GO!
もう一回セーノ!
One more time, ready!
ハイ! ハイ! ゼンリョク!
Hai! Hai! Full power!
私は こんなんじゃない!
I am, this can't be all there is!
Great Days
[Title: Great Days]
Shining justice 芽生えてく
Shining justice, starts to bloom
Brand new bed town 交差する息吹
Brand new bed town, a fresh breath arrives
岬から潮風 トンネル抜け鉄塔へ
A sea breeze from that tunnel, heading for the tower
引かれ合い小道に迷い込む
Drawn to one another, losing our way down lanes
ココロに溶け込む影
A shadow melts into our hearts
照らす黄金の“Spirits”
Heading for a golden spirit soul
それは守り抜く光
A light to protect our only one
Let the voice of love take you higher!
集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
With this gathered power, go beyond even time
1999 Bizarre Summer
巡る勇気で生きる町
This city thrives on revolving courage
巡る勇気で生きる街
Great Days
Breakdown Breakdown!
Song of praises 響かせ
Song of praises sounds out
Brand new up town すれ違う景色
Brand new up town, scenery passes by
雲の切れ間に射す光がほら降り注ぎ
From a break in the clouds, look, light is pouring through
イニシエの小道へ誘い込む
Being invited into the ancient narrow lanes
煌めき導く町
A town that leads to a sparkle
たぎる黄金の"Spirits"それは果てしない絆
Boiling golden "Spirits", they are our never-ending bonds
Let the joy of love give you an answer
別れの時さえ砕けぬ意思で
With a purpose that's unbreakable even when we part
1999年 Bizarre Summer
1999 Bizarre Summer
自分乗り越え掴み取れ未来
Surpassing ourselves and grabbing the future
Breakdown Breakdown!
Let the voice of love take you higher
集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
With this gathered power, go beyond even time
Let the joy of love give you an answer
別れの時さえ砕けぬ意思で
With a purpose that's unbreakable even when we part
1999年 Bizarre Summer
1999 Bizarre Summer
交わす勇気が生む讃歌
The courage we exchange will birth our hymn
Great Days
Breakdown Breakdown!
はい、というわけで、Great Daysをお届けしました！
So, we just performed 'Great Days'!
みんな楽しんでくれましたか？
Did everyone enjoy it?
ここまではですね、まず「メニシキラシュシュ」
Up until now, first was 'Menishiki Rashushu',
この曲はですね、スバルもうめっちゃね、
this song, for me, well...
この曲は元々大好きで、絶対にやろうって決めてたんですけど、
I've always loved it and decided I'd definitely do it.
その結果ね、見事ね、ウマ娘のアプリめっちゃやるようになりました。ありがとうございます。
As a result, I've ended up playing the Uma Musume app a lot. Thank you!
そんな大好きな楽曲をみんなとできてとっても楽しかったです！
I was so happy to perform such a favorite song with everyone!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
そして続いて、百花繚乱でカッコよく踊りました。
And then, we danced coolly to 'Hyakka Ryouran'.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
このひらひらがですね、結構難しくて頑張ったんですけど、
These fluttering parts were quite difficult, but I worked hard...
見てくれましたか？
Did you see it?
でもすごく踊って楽しかったです。
But it was very fun to dance.
そしてですね、「こんなんじゃない」！
And then, 'Konna n ja nai'!
この曲はですね、夢叶いしものになった時点で絶対にやろうと思ってたんですけど、
I'd been thinking of doing this song since the moment I 'achieved my dream'...
ノエちゃんとつうに 絶対にペンライト振ってほしいと思って、呼ばせていただきました。
I really wanted Noel-chan and others to wave their penlights, so I invited them.
どうだったかなみんな？ 楽しんでもらえたらとっても嬉しいです。
How was it, everyone? I'm very happy if you enjoyed it.
そしてGreat Daysはですね、スバルの大好きなジョジョ4部の曲なんですけど、
And 'Great Days' is a song from JoJo Part 4, which I love...
この…もう絶対に！これでバトンをするんだと、こうしてぐるぐるぐるぐる回して…
I definitely wanted to use the baton for this, spinning it around like this...
今年もね、飛ばさせていただいたんですけど、
I also let it fly this year too.
みんなスバルの「魂」と書いて「プライド」と読む、
Did you all see this baton of my soul...
この魂のバトンを見ていただけましたか？
written as 'soul' but read as 'Pride'?
もう凄かったんだから、本当に。
It was really amazing, honestly.
ということで、そんなスバルのこだわりと思いがいっぱい詰まったパートにさせていただきました。
So, I made this part full of my dedication and feelings.
そしてなんと！ここからは嬉しいお知らせとなっております。
And now! From here, we have some happy news.
なんと！大空スバル7周年記念ライブのグッズ販売告知！
Announcement of Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live merchandise sales!
こちらをご覧ください！
Please take a look at this!
グッズは4種類あります。めちゃめちゃある。ということで早速見ていきましょう！
There are 4 types of merch. Quite a lot. Let's take a look right away!
イラストはしぐれうい先生に描いていただきました。母ちゃんいつもありがとう！
The illustration was drawn by Shigure Ui-sensei. Thanks as always, Mom!
イラストテーマは「王道アイドルスバル」です。
The illustration theme is 'Classic Idol Subaru'.
それでは詳細を見ていきましょう。まずは、こちら！
Now let's look at the details. First is this!
スバルがファンサ！ラバーマット。
Subaru Fanservice! Rubber Mat.
さー！
Alright!
こちらの情報は、王道アイドルのスバルが描いてあるラバーマットになります！
This is a rubber mat featuring Subaru as a royal idol!
以前ラバーマットを出したのは、えーと、4年前なので
The last time I released a rubber mat was... uh, 4 years ago.
当時買えなかった人もね、前のも使っててもうボロボロになっちゃったよーっていう人も
So for those who couldn't get it then, or those whose old one is worn out...
ぜひ新しくチェックしてみてくださーい！
Please check out the new one!
そして、続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
スバルがファンサ！カードスリーブ！
Subaru Fanservice! Card Sleeves!
こちらはですね、ラバーマットに合わせてカードスリーブも出してみました！
I've released card sleeves to match the rubber mat!
ラバーマットと合わせて使えば、スバルに応援されているような気持ちになれるかもということで
Using them together might make you feel like Subaru is cheering you on,
ぜひこちらも要チェックですよー！
so definitely check these out too!
そして、続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
マスコット大集合カードケース！イエーイ！
Mascot Gathering Card Case! Yay!
カードスリーブときたらね、やっぱりケースも必要でしょうということで
Since we have sleeves, we definitely need a case too.
もうスバルのスバルドダックから、なんと、うたうさぎまで
From Subarudo Duck to even Uta-Usagi...
たくさんのみんなが集まった、えー、カードケースを作ってみました！
I made a card case with all of them gathered together!
側面はですね、カードを見せつけられる窓がついているので
The side has a window so you can show off your card,
今回のカードスリーブをパシャっと挿して見せるもよし
so you can display the new card sleeve...
そのね、切り札を見せつけるもよしということで、ぜひこちらもチェックしてみてください！
...or show off your trump card! Please check it out!
そして、最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー、動物パジャマ衣装バージョン！
Plush Keychain, Animal Pajama Outfit Version!
こちらはですね、なんかスバル自身のぬいぐるみってあまり出してないかも？と思ったので
I realized I haven't released a plush of myself before,
アイドル衣装と対になるイメージのオフっぽい動物パジャマ衣装で作ってみました！
so I made one in an 'off-duty' style animal pajama outfit to contrast the idol look!
ぜひね、このかわちいスバルもいろんなところに連れまわしてみてください！
Please take this cute Subaru with you everywhere!
そしてなんと！フルセット購入特典もあります！
And what's more, there's a full set purchase bonus!
それではこちら！ドン！
Here it is! Bam!
ステッカーがなんとね、今回ついております！とってもかわいい！
It comes with a sticker this time! It's so cute!
スバルずっと前からステッカー出してみたいなーってずっと思ってたので、夢がかなって嬉しいです！
I've wanted to make stickers for a long time, so I'm happy my dream came true!
ぜひみんなのお気に入りの場所にぺたっと貼ってみてください！
Please stick them in your favorite places!
そしてでは、改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！ドン！
Once again, here is the full set! Bam!
やっぱりね、買うならね、シールもついてお得なフルセットの方がいいかも？
The full set is a better deal since it includes the sticker!
以上、大空スバル7周年記念ライブ'のグッズ情報でしたー！
That was the goods info for Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live!
どれもですね、素敵なグッズに仕上がっておりますので、ぜひ要チェックだ！
They're all wonderful items, so be sure to check them out!
絶対にチェックしてくださいね！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Make sure to check them out! Thank you!
はい、そしてですね、なんとこの衣装でのニュースバル、ちょっとね、
Also, 'New Subaru' in this outfit is...
かわいいのでとっても、ぜひスクリーンショット撮っていただきたいです！
...really cute, so please take some screenshots!
わー！
Wow!
あ、そっか、後ろ向いたら撮れないや。どうぞ！
Oh, right, if I turn around you can't see me. There you go!
かわいいですか？
Is it cute?
スバルのこのね、衣装のね、好きポイントはですね、この後ろの...
My favorite part of this outfit is the back...
とってもかわいいリボンがですね、かわいい！
...these really cute ribbons! So cute!
どうですか？
What do you think?
わー！かわいい！
Wow! Cute!
え、マジで語彙力ないな、今日。でもほんとに可愛いので、
Ugh, I really have no vocabulary today. But it's truly cute,
ぜひみんないっぱいポストしてください！よろしくお願いします！
so please post lots of pictures! Thank you!
そしてですね、こんなに楽しいライブも、もう、なんと終盤！わー！
And now, this fun live is already nearing the end! Wow!
ということで、ここからはラストに向けてバーっと駆け抜けていきたいと思いますので、
So from here, I'm going to rush towards the end!
ぜひみんなもね、最後まで楽しんでいただけると、すごく嬉しいです！
I'd be very happy if you all enjoy it until the very end!
はい、ということで。
Alright then.
それじゃあもう、ラストだよ！始めちゃっていいわけ？
It's already the last song! Are you ready to start?
始めちゃうよ。ということで、それじゃあですね、
I'm starting. Well then...
よし、始めたいと思います。よいしょよいしょ。ポーズ取って。
Alright, let's begin. Strike a pose.
はい、それでは聴いてください。「ray」。
Yes, please listen to: 'ray'.
ray
作詞・作曲：藤原基央
[Title: ray]
[Lyrics/Composition: Fujiwara Motoo]
お別れしたのはもっと 前の事だったような
Saying goodbye was something that happened a long time ago
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
I sealed away the sad light and wore down my heels
うおー
Whoa—
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
I could see it when I was with you, but now I can no longer see it
透明な彗星をぼんやりと...
I vaguely look for that transparent comet...
でもそれだけ探している
but that's all I'm searching for.
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ
I often sang songs,
その時だけのメロディーを
melodies for just that moment.
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely,
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ
I always used to sing songs
その時だけのメロディーを
With melodies only for that moment
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely at all
ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
Because I was able to properly feel lonely
いつまで
Until when
どこまでなんて
To where, and such
正常か
Whether it's normal
異常かなんて
Or abnormal
考える暇も無い程
To the point that there's no time to even think
歩くのは大変だ
Walking is such a struggle
楽しい方がずっといいよ
It's much better to have fun
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll keep on smiling through it all
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it
理想で作った道を
The path I made with ideals
現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality continues to paint over it
思い出はその軌跡の上で
Memories remain on that trajectory
輝きになって残っている
And stay there as a shining light
お別れしたのは何で
Why did we say goodbye?
何のためだったんだろうな
What was it all for, I wonder?
悲しい光が僕の影を
The sad light stretches my shadow
前に長く伸ばしている
Far out in front of me
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever
時間がある時眠るよ
I sleep when I have time
夢だと解るその中で
In the midst of a dream I know is a dream
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll see you, and then keep going again
晴天とはほど遠い
So far from a clear sky
終わらない暗闇にも
Even in this endless darkness
星を思い浮かべたなら
If I can just imagine the stars
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'll be right in the middle of a galaxy
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore
靴を新しくしても
Even if I get new shoes
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it
伝えたかった事が
Things I wanted to tell you...
きっとあったんだろうな
...must have surely existed
恐らくありきたり
They were probably just ordinary
なんだろうけど こんなにも
...but even so, they mean this much
お別れした事は
The fact that we said goodbye
出会った事と繋がっている
Is connected to the fact that we met
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet
透明だから無くならない
Won't disappear because it's transparent
◯×△どれかなんて
Whether it's a circle, cross, or triangle
皆と比べてどうかなんて
How it compares to everyone else
確かめる間も無い程
To the point that there's no time to verify
生きるのは最高だ
Living is the best thing there is
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll keep on smiling through it all
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it
大丈夫だ
It's okay
この光の始まりには
At the beginning of this light...
君がいる
...you are there
シルエット
[Title: Silhouette]
いっせーのーせで
Ready, set, go
踏み込むゴーライン
Step over the goal line
僕らは何も何もまだ知らぬ
We don't know, don't know anything yet
一線越えて
Crossing the line
振り返るともうない
Looking back, it's already gone
僕らは何も何もまだ知らぬ
We don't know, don't know anything yet
うだってうだってうだってく
Dazzled, dazzled, we're dazzled
煌めく汗がこぼれるのさ
Glistening sweat trickles down
覚えてないこともたくさんあっただろう
There must have been many things we've forgotten
I'm sure there were many things we've forgotten
たくさんあっただろう
There were many, weren't there?
誰も彼も
Everyone, everything,
シルエット
the silhouettes
大事にしてたもの、忘れたフリをしたんだよ
We pretended to forget the things we held dear, didn't we?
なにもないよ、笑えるさ
There's nothing left, we can laugh about it
いっせーのーで、
With a one, two,
思い出す少年
I remember the young boy
僕らはなにもかもを欲しがった
We wanted everything, everything
わかってるって、あぁ気づいてるって
I get it, ah, I've realized it
時計の針は日々は止まらない
The hands of the clock, the days won't stop
奪って
Stealing
奪ってく
Stealing away
流れる時と記憶
The flowing time and memories
遠く遠く
Far, far away
遠くになって
They become far, far away
覚えてないこともたくさんあっただろう
I'm sure there were many things we've forgotten
誰も彼もシルエット
Everyone, everything, the silhouettes
恐れてやまぬこと、
The things we feared,
知らないフリをしたんだよ
we pretended not to know, didn't we?
なにもないよ、笑えるさ
There's nothing left, we can laugh about it
ひらりとひらりと舞ってる
Lightly, lightly dancing
木の葉の様に憂うことなく
Like leaves, without anxiety
焦燥もなく過ごしていたいよ
I want to spend my days without impatience
覚えてないこともたくさんあったけど
I'm sure there were many things we've forgotten, but
きっとずっと変わらないものがあることを
Surely, the things that never change exist
教えてくれたあなたは
You taught me that
消えぬ消えぬシルエット
The silhouette that never disappears
大事にしたいもの持って大人になるんだ
Hold onto the things you want to cherish as you become an adult
どんな時も離さずに守り続けよう
Let's keep protecting them without ever letting go
そしたらいつの日にか
And then, someday
なにもかもを笑えるさ
we'll be able to laugh about everything
ひらりとひらりと舞ってる
Lightly, lightly dancing
木の葉が飛んでゆく
Leaves are flying away
スターライト
[Title: StarLight]
描いた未知のキャンパス重ねる景色
Scenery overlapping on the unknown canvas I painted
繋いでみて繰り返してく衝動
Try connecting, the repeating impulse
揺らいだ目の前に広がる世界
The world spreading out before my wavering eyes
星屑のメロディ歌に乗せた
A melody of stardust, set to a song
クラっと鮮やかに眩ませるように
Vividly dizzying, as if to dazzle
駆け抜けるよスターライト
I'll run through, StarLight
そう僕らはいつしか夢の中引かれて
Yes, we were drawn into a dream before we knew it
ただがむしゃらに走り続けたよ
I just kept running recklessly
無限の宇宙に響いた
Resonated in the infinite universe
キミを照らす声は
The voice that shines on you
どこへだってきらり飛んでゆけるんだ
Can sparkle and fly to you anywhere
愉快な仲間と歩いた非日常
The extraordinary days I walked with my fun friends
刻んでみて指先の一等星
Try engraving, the first-magnitude star at your fingertips
滲んでゆく目の前に広がった限界は
The limits that spread before my blurring eyes
みんなの手重ねてぶっ壊して
I'll smash them by overlapping everyone's hands
吸い込まれそうな夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that seems to swallow me
今叫ぶよスターライト
I'll scream it now, StarLight
そう僕らはいつでも側で笑い合って
Yes, we are always laughing together by each other's side
あふれる声が遠くこだまする
Overflowing voices echo far away
願いの
Of my wish...
スターライト
Starlight
願いのかけらを灯した
I lit up the fragments of my wishes
キミの腕を引いて どこへだってきらり飛んでゆけるんだ
Pulling your arm, we can fly anywhere, sparkling
ちょこっと不安な日も
Even on days when I'm a little anxious
魔法をかけてハッピー
I'll cast a spell and be happy
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with a hundred-man power
アクアブルーに染まる
Targeting the blue-dyed sky
大空にめがけた
鼓動が弾んでく
My heartbeat keeps bouncing
We can fly そう僕らは
We can fly, that's right, us
この日をずっと待ってたんだ
We've been waiting for this day forever
まだ醒めないでStarlight
Don't wake up yet, Starlight
僕らは止まらない
We won't stop
その光が消える1秒前まで
Until one second before the light disappears
走り続けるよ
We'll keep running
無限の宇宙に響いたキミを照らす声を
The voice echoing in the infinite universe and illuminating you
強く抱いてきらり輝いてゆけ
Clutching it tight, shine and go, sparkling
ラブミ！
Love Me!
いつだって愛情が先に
Love always comes first
走り出す僕らのランウェイを
On our runway that's starting to move
頑丈とラッキーを盾に
With sturdiness and luck as my shield
進みますアーユーレディー？
I'll move forward, are you ready?
転んだって泣いたって僕ら
Even if we fall or cry
慣れてるよ受け身はパーフェクト
We're used to it, our breakfall is perfect
笑ってくれてありがと！
Thank you for smiling for me!
また僕は歌えるよ
Now I can sing again
人生は不安ばっか正直自信はないけど
Life is full of anxiety, honestly I'm not confident
君の隣だけは譲る気はないのです！
But I have no intention of giving up the spot next to you!
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ
The miraculous world where we met
君の眼にどう映るかな
How does it look in your eyes?
青より澄み渡る希望
A hope that is clearer than blue
僕だけの大空だといいな
I hope it's an 'Oozora' just for me
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity
二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
I want to sing about the 'now' we spend together
この惑星の片隅続く
Continuing in a corner of this planet
あいまいミーゆえにラブミー
Because of the ambiguous me, Love Me!
ナンセンスな現実が 心を乱していった
Nonsense reality disturbed my heart
ラッキーの天秤の 裏側にあるアンラッキー
On the other side of the scale of luck is unluckiness
転んだって泣いたって僕ら
Even if we fall or cry
立ち上がる七転八倒さ
We'll stand up, through all the ups and downs
笑ってくれてありがto!
Thank you for smiling for me!
まだ僕は走れるよ
I can still keep running
人生の期待感は正直膨らむばっかでさ
The expectations for life honestly just keep expanding
君の心の中 灯るひだまりなのです
Inside your heart, it's a sunny spot that lights up
僕らが暮らしてる奇跡の時代
The miraculous era we live in
君のコトどう照らすかな
How will it illuminate you?
星より煌めいた
Brighter than the stars
僕らしい太陽になれたら
If I could become a sun like myself
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity
二人で過ごす今を楽しんでいたい
I want to enjoy the 'now' we spend together
この惑星の片隅続く
Continuing in a corner of this planet
あいまいミーゆえにダンシング
Because of the ambiguous me, Dancing!
今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for today!
ここまで活動できたのは応援してくれたみんなのおかげです！
Being able to come this far is thanks to everyone who supported me!
いつも本当にありがとう！みんな大好きだぞー！
Thank you always! I love you all!
ああ健やかな時も
Ah, in health
ああ病める時もきっと
Ah, and in sickness, surely
伝えたいよこのメロディー
I want to convey this melody
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ
The miraculous world where we met
君の眼にどう映るかな
How does it look in your eyes?
青より澄み渡る希望
A hope that is clearer than blue
僕だけの大空だといいな
I hope it's an 'Oozora' just for me
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity
二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
I want to sing about the 'now' we spend together
この惑星の片隅続く
Continuing in a corner of this planet
あいまいミーゆえにラブミー
Because of the ambiguous me, Love Me!
アイラブユー伝えたいの！
I want to tell you, I love you!
これからも、楽しい事いっぱい一緒にはね！
Let's keep doing lots of fun things together!!!